<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The rebels association in Hungary for reformation of religion and advancement of the Empire</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 8KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A58283</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11893606</idno>
  <idno type="VID">50481</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248528049</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing R598</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R5775</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">11893606</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A58283)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 50481)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 507:27)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The rebels association in Hungary for reformation of religion and advancement of the Empire</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1682]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Broadside.</note>
                  <note>A satire.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  London --  17th century</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="satire">
            <pb facs="tcp:50481:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>The Rebels Association</hi> IN HUNGARY. FOR Reformation of RELIGION, and Advance<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the EMPIRE.</head>
            <p>THE Teckelites are in Discipline and Principles much the same with those they call Whigs in <hi>England,</hi> Religion being the ground of all their Exorbitances. Under pretence of Religion (which is indeed but Rebellion,) they will Levy Arms against the Emperour, and for Defence of the Gospel, join with the Turk against their Christian Sovereign. They are great Admirers of <hi>Hopkins</hi> and <hi>Sternhold,</hi> and Love the <hi>Psalms</hi> above any part of Canonical Scripture, because it mentions, the Binding of Kings in Chains, and their Nobles in Fetters. Fear God and Honour the King, is their <hi>Apocripha.</hi> The Beast with the many Horns, their <hi>Revelations.</hi> The Seditious City, who in Defence of their Liberties, dare lose their Charter, and forfeit their Indentures, to become Free-men. They are for a King too, provided it be a Rebel, and of their own Choosing, and being so Chosen, to Change him as oft as they shall think fit. Yet never did Rebels carry it on with greater pretence of Loyalty, then these Teckelites; when at the very same time, they were Enter'd into an Association to Levy War, to Rout out Religion and Monarchy, and undermine the very Foundation of the Empire, as you will find it in the following Association,</p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The ASSOCIATION.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>We the Noblemen, Warbeck Princes, Crawling Counts, Bulky Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rons, Bully Knights, Silly Squires, Coxcomb Cits, Brumingham Bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gesses, Buggering Parsons, and Seditious Commons, of all Sorts, Sects and Factions, in the Kingdom of</hi> Hungary, <hi>having before our Eyes, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>he Grievances of the Empire, and Arbitrary Tyranny, the Advance<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ent of a Common-Wealth, and the true Reformed Protestant Religi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n, with the Ancient Rights, Liberties and Properties of the People, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> have after mature Deliberation, many Sacred Cabals at the Devil, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd Religious Conventicles at</hi> Ferguson<hi>'s,) Resolved and Determin'd, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>o enter into a mutual League and Association, wherein we all Subscribe, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd every Man for himself doth Swear,</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="1">1. That we Enter into an Association, with a sincere Constancy, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nd fixed Resolution, Resolutely to withstand and oppose every <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ing that shall stand up for the Church or Government, and Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>each all such, as Enemies to the Establish'd Religion, &amp; the Empire.</p>
               <p n="2">2. That we shall Sincerely, Really and Constantly, throw the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>untain of Grace, the Inspiring Spigget, Endeavour, in our se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Places and Callings, Councils and Cabals, the Preservation of the true Blew Reformed Protestant Religion, to the intent, that Sedition may be openly Profes'd, Rebellion Countenanc'd, and Treason not only Encourag'd, but Publickly Taught and Promoted in every Coffee-House, and Conventicle.</p>
               <p n="3">
                  <pb facs="tcp:50481:2"/>3. That we shall, without Respect of Pe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>sons, e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>av<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>r the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tirpation of Popery and Prelacy, (that is, Church Government, by Arch-Bishops, Bishops, Deans, Chapters,) Superstition, Idolatry, Prophaness, or whatever shall be found co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>rary <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>o <hi>J<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>lian</hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postate, and the true Form of Godliness.</p>
               <p n="4">4. And that we may have some show of Loyalty, as well as Godli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness, tho' we deny the Power thereof, we will join in this Association, for the Preservation of His Majesties Person, and to Secure the Impe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rial Crown in His Posterity, that the World may bear Witness with our Consciences, of our Loyalty, and that we have no Thoughts nor Intentions, to diminish His Imperial Majesties Just Power and Gr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness. For the Defence of His Person, we will Cut off His Guards, and lay Stratagems &amp; Ambuscades against His Life. To clear our selves after all this, if our Stratagems at any time take Effect, we will Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vevenge His Death on the Papists, under which Notion we will De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroy all the Imperial Loyalists in Church and State, and Conclude, whoever is not a Protestant Teckelite in open Rebellion, must be an Imperial Papist.</p>
               <p n="5">5. We will Secure the Imperial Crown in His Posterity, by bringing in a Bill of Exclusion to cast off the Succession, and make <hi>Teckley</hi> Emperour.</p>
               <p n="6">6. Lastly, we will make him Great, Powerful and Glorious.</p>
               <p n="1">1. Great by giving him no Mony, and Voting it Treason for any that do it. 2. Powerful, by endeavouring to Lessen him abroad and Rendring him odious at home, by Seditious Libels, Speeches and Appeals. 3. Glorious, by sending him to seek a more Glorious Crown in another World.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And this Association we make at the Devil aforesaid, in the presence of his Blessed Angels, with a true Intention to perform the same as we shall Answer at the great Day when the Secresy of all Hearts shall be Disclos'd, for till then we will never Confess a word tho we be taken in the very Fact, but Resolve to Die Justifying our Innocence, Loyalty and Integrity to the last. And to this Association and every particular thereof, we have set our Hands and Seals at the Devil aforesaid, on the Night of the True Protestant Try<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>umph, and the Popes Procession to the Porch of the Temple,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>
                     <list>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Teckley</hi> Prince <hi>Perkinburg</hi> King Elect of the Rebels.</item>
                        <item>The <hi>Suir Tapsbury Grimace,</hi> President of the Committee.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Russelhumburg—</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Grayford Lightthank.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Gogglebrow Brandonbury.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Algernoon Rout-Guard.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Hampdenham,</hi> Collonels of the Insur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Trenchardi,</hi> Collonels of the Insur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Bully Armstrong,</hi> Knight and Champion to the King of <hi>Hungary.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Rumbold, Rouse, Thompson, Wade, Hone, Walcot, Nelthorp, Goodenough,</hi> &amp;c. The <hi>Banditti</hi> King-Killers &amp; Assassinators.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Tytus,</hi> The Salamanca Doctor.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Groning Board,</hi> Father Confessor to the Innocent Traytors.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Ferguson,</hi> Chaplin to the President of the Committee.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Castiers,</hi> &amp;c. Incendiaries and Promoters of the Rebellion.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Step. Colledg,</hi> The First Martyr.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Aron Smith,</hi> The Protestant Sollicitor.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Rouse, Hone, Walcot,</hi> Proto-Martyrs.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Hamborow Betheliski,</hi> Head Master to the Rebels.</item>
                        <item>Colonel <hi>Roderigo.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Mansilburgh,</hi> Evidences in Ordinary.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Hethorington,</hi> Evidences in Ordinary.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Milesbury ap Rance,</hi> Evidance on either side.</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Rick Janewarg, Dick Buldenburg, H. Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burrow, L. Curtis-horn.</hi> Publick Nota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, Libellars and Pamphlatiers to stir up Sedition, and keep the Teke<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lites in Arms and Rebellion against the Emperor.</item>
                     </list>
                  </signed>
               </closer>
               <postscript>
                  <p>There were a Thousand more that put their Hand to this Association, who never Signed an Address. But not being worth the Naming, I refer them to <hi>Jack Katch</hi>'s Catalogue where you will find 'em Quoted more at large.</p>
               </postscript>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>